When preparing for this interview, I
spent a few hours hunting with my
guest's methodology just to prepare and
ask a bit better questions. But to my
surprise, I found a bug even though I
was already top three of this program on
HackerOne. And even better, by the time
I'm recording this intro, I already
found two more bugs on the same program.
So, I don't know what a better
recommendation could I give you to
listen to my interview with Douglas Day.
Enjoy. Hello Douglas, thank you so much
for joining me for the interview today.
For those viewers who don't know you
yet, can you please introduce yourself a
little bit and tell us how did you start
with bug bounties?
Sure. Yeah, so my name is Douglas Day or
Archangel on most platforms.
I've been doing bug bounties since
October of 20 18.
And I got my bounty my first my first
bounty in December of 2018. What was
what kind of kicked off my journey was I
was working at a
company at the time that had a bug
bounty program on HackerOne.
It was New Relic. I started there I
think that summer.
And I had never heard of HackerOne
before joining the company and I
joined their application security team
expecting to look at scan reports and
boring security data that nobody cares
about. But they threw me onto the
HackerOne platform and to start triaging
bugs that we were getting from real
hackers.
And it was intriguing because this was a
This was a SaaS application that
companies were paying a lot of money for
and here were actual vulnerabilities
that real hackers were finding like
cross-site scripting vulnerabilities or
IDORs or privilege escalations or
paywall bypasses. And I was like, "Wow,
this is a This isn't just a sandbox.
This isn't a CTF. This is a a real
application and there are real bugs in
here." And so after a few months of
looking at these um
at these reports coming in, I
my wife and I were talking and wanted to
buy our first house. And I said, "Okay,
well, maybe this is a good opportunity
to to earn some extra money on the on
the side." And I spun up my account in
October of 2018.
And I didn't have children at the time
and so I would just spend my afternoons
and evenings looking for
looking for bugs and got my first one on
the Coinbase program
in December of 2018. And I I shudder
thinking about it because it was just a
like a rate limit bypass.
It was not very exciting at all. It was
a low. But it was a $200 bounty and I
was stoked. And it just got me hooked.
And I went into 2019 expecting to
you know, make make a you know, a couple
hundred dollars a month, but I almost
ended up matching my
my engineering salary just with bug
bounty alone in 2019 and that's when I
realized that shoot, this is there's
really something to this. And now fast
forward to
and here I am
quitting my day job a couple couple
weeks ago and now doing this doing this
full time and mixing in a bit of
consulting in there to to have some
steady consistent income, but for the
most part doing bug bounty full time and
it's Yeah, it's been awesome. It's been
a It's been a life-changing experience.
This house that I'm I'm standing in
right now was was built with entirely
with bug bounties.
Oh, so you made the
achieved the goal that you initially,
you know, set up when starting bug
bounties. That's so cool.
What what made you
switch the the the decision make the
decision to to go full time?
I think I started getting So, I I built
a family. I have three children now and
my afternoons and and weekends are less
free. And so I found myself getting
frustrated that I couldn't spend as much
time hacking as I as I wanted to because
obviously during the day I want to
to dedicate my time to my to the job
that I'm being paid to do. And so I
found it really difficult to to find
time to
to do bug bounty. And so I thought,
"Okay, well, what if this was my my
full-time job and the expectation was
that I was I would be doing bug bounty
during the day.
And then get to spend my afternoons and
evenings with my with my family."
And so I I
started thinking about that a couple
years ago, probably in 2022.
But just didn't work up the courage to
Yeah, well, yeah, it cuz it's scary.
It's it's scary bug You know, I have I
have a family and a lot of bills to pay
and got very comfortable on you know, a
United States tech salary. And so
quitting my
quitting my day job
at a you know, a very well-paid paid job
and going for something as inconsistent
and unreliable as bug bounty was
was really scary. And so it did take me
a couple years to build up a a very
solid financial foundation so that so
that I didn't have to worry about money
if I had some slow months and
and be able to take some risk. And now
here here I am. I don't I don't
recommend people take as as long as I
did if they decide to make the jump.
I think I probably took way longer than
I needed to, but um
just I was
I let I let fear control me for for
longer than I should.
What were the the things that you did to
prepare yourself once you already made
the decision that you want to quit? But
I imagine you had a few months still of
of your contract and what did you do in
this time?
Yeah, so I I made the decision I think
in like February of this year. I had
just gotten back from a
the Miami live hacking event with
HackerOne
focused on Capital One and I got the the
MVH there and
it was a very sizable
bounty amount.
I had made a sizable amount on bounties
at the event and I I realized, "Okay,
this this is probably doable at this
point. I'm I just had my best month
ever, my best event ever.
I've been thinking about this for years.
I need to make the jump. So, how do I
make that happen?"
And so
what I did is I
I decided, "Okay, how much how much do I
need to be able to
give myself like four months of of
runway?" And so I took that number
um
just set aside a couple of stock vests
that were coming in through my through
my company cuz I would get paid in stock
every three months. And so after two
stock vests, one I got in in March of
this year and then when I got in June of
this year,
I just set those aside to be used as a
four months of runway.
And
uh
waited waited until I got those stock
vests and then and then put in my
notice. And so that's what I did to
prepare just set aside four months. I I
have if I only had those four months, I
don't think I would have had the courage
to to make the jump.
But I
have also built up a a pretty solid you
know, safety net of investments such
that I can my family can last
significantly longer if we need to. I
would rather not touch those
investments. So so this this this like
four months of runway is just in my
checking account ready to be to be
pulled from at at the beginning of every
month. So at the you know, on
July 1st, I took or on August 1st, I'll
take you know,
however much money that I need for for
one month and then move it from that
that envelope into my
into my current expenses and then I'll
just spend the first couple weeks of or
the first week or week or two of
of August building that back up and then
saving and investing the rest after
that. So that's kind of my strategy
going forward just building up the
my runway for the next month and just to
make sure that I always keep four months
of of build up. And then and then
anything extra I save and invest and um
we'll probably look to buy look to buy
my next house in the next few years and
so save up towards that or
put money towards
you know, a rental or some other expense
that we need like a family vacation or
something. So.
Yeah, for for me it's to some
I want to do it like this that I just
have the account from which I pay myself
the same amount every month. But I I've
never
gotten to do it and it's just a bit
chaotic cuz also I have different types
of income for different accounts. One
thing is in PayPal, the other is in the
bank account. And it's just you know,
when when I my normal account runs out
of money, I transfer from one of these
accounts. But I really think it's smart
to just you know, pay yourself a salary
just like you would be employed. And
then when you earn, put it into this
this account and have it like organized
a little bit less. I probably should
think about it.
Do you Do you have a family?
That's what made me have to get
organized. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And lots
more responsibilities. Yeah, that's
that's true. Yeah.
And yeah, also with with three children.
I understand your decision cuz cuz I
imagine you just had no free time left
when you do did bug bounties as a hobby
after hours. So
So yeah, I see.
Okay, let's
let's get more into into hacking itself.
What is What is your hacking style? What
are your favorite vulnerability classes?
Yeah, so I'd say
over 50% of my bugs are privilege
escalations
and then maybe another 30% are IDORs.
I I really like privilege escalations
because they're really hard to protect
against. And
endpoints typically have to be fixed or
patched on a per endpoint basis. And so
there's not there's not as many holistic
fixes to
to privilege escalations, especially if
you've got a very complicated permission
structure.
I know you were DMing me before this
before this call about something that
you like you went and found and
and sure enough, you know, you were just
took a look at
Okay, you got a user with with this
permission, can they hit this endpoint?
And I mean that's my that's my bread and
butter. And so I
these there's just so many applications,
especially in this world of
of SaaS, where you've got uh
you know, five different permission
levels and then maybe like 300 different
endpoints that a user can make and then
you just
go through and find the ones that you're
not supposed to be able to call and
hopefully it leaks a lot of information
or it does something that's impactful.
And if it can bypass like a an
organization boundary or a tenant
boundary such that you can like affect
people that you're not supposed to be
working with,
then that's even that's even better and
that'll increase the increase the
impact. And so that's that's mostly what
I I look for. I've been
I've been on a kick lately of doing
uh
like uh payment bypasses or price
manipulation. And so I've been looking
at store applications and trying to get
myself things for free just because
they're really fun to talk about. Um
in fact, I found a really cool one
yesterday.
Uh
and
which uses a like a concept of like uh
loyalty or reward points. So like the
more you buy on a particular store, you
like get credit uh to be able to get
discounts. And so you know, you might
spend like
$100 and then
your next purchase you get like $1 off.
Or if you spend you know, $200 you get
$2 off of your next purchase. And I I
found a way to basically generate
unlimited points so that you can
get everything for free.
Uh and so I've been I've been doing a
lot of those recently just because
they're fun to talk about with friends
and family.
You know, if you're if you're at a party
and you
you're talking about hacking
to somebody who's not really technical
or isn't in the bug bounty space, you
know, you could say, "Oh, I got
cross-site scripting or I got RCE." And
they'd be like,
"Okay, whatever." But if you tell them
that, "Oh yeah, you can buy
you know, free alcohol for life." Um
then they're like, "Oh, that's awesome,
dude. You need to you need to teach me
how to hack so I can get myself some
beer." And it's uh it's
it's just way more way more fun to talk
about. I've been in addition to price
manipulation and uh payment bypasses,
I've also been doing a lot of uh blind
XSS. Um that's been kind of a a
vulnerability that's newer to me. I just
found maybe like my second one ever a
couple weeks ago, but it was it was just
super fun because it's it's like a a
treasure hunt, right? You never know if
you're going to be getting
getting like a callback and you just put
the put the
uh blind XSS payload in different input
input fields and then
suddenly, you know, a few days later you
see some admin panel pop up on your
on your XSS hunter and you're like,
"Whoa, it looks like that you know, that
request I made 3 days ago finally hit
somebody and now I can
you know, delete any account in the
application." And so the the um
the impact is typically pretty pretty
high.
Yeah.
Yeah, of course of course for for people
that's
that that watch watch the interview, I
obviously prepared a lot for for the
interview. I knew that the Douglas style
includes a lot of looking for privilege
escalation bugs. So yesterday I decided
what better way to prepare for the
interview than to just spend a few hours
hacking in this way.
So I just opened the application that I
was quite familiar with and I to be
honest, I never tested authorization
because it is a lot of work. Like when
you talk about it sometimes in podcast,
like, "Yeah, just do a matrix of of
roles and and permissions." And it
sounds like a few checks. But when you
take a look at how many roles there are,
how many permissions there are, and how
many endpoints are in a single
functionality, that's a lot of work.
That's a lot of work and that's why also
why I didn't do it a lot in the past.
But yesterday I decided, you know, I I I
will give it a go and and just in a few
hours I found a bug.
To be honest, I feel like I've cheated a
little bit because
there was a a lot of endpoints and I was
it's an open source target. So I I
looked at the source code at how do they
check for authorization?
It's also one of the reason that that it
is actually what you mentioned that it
is really hard to for example write a
scanner rule to detect authorization
privilege bypasses or authorization
bypasses cuz it's like it's never the
same.
Uh but I just
I looked kind of almost manually at at
how do they check permissions on
different code and I saw some strange
logic and that's how I found a bug.
Uh and it's already 3 years so
thank you for this, but
uh yeah, my first question, how do you
get the persistence to check through as
you said hundreds of endpoints with
different roles?
So I typically will have a pretty good
idea after maybe like an hour of testing
whether or not it's going to be very
fruitful. Like if if if I don't find
anything in an hour and I'm like, "Okay,
it looks like they
they're doing a pretty good job in
general." Then I'm not going to spend,
you know, another 8 hours just grinding
and banging my head against the wall
because I don't have that kind of
persistence. But
I mean when you when you're finding a
bug every like
hour or 90 minutes or you half an hour,
um it just gives you that that
excitement and that rush to just keep
going for like another another hour or
two. It's like, "Oh, I bet there's
another endpoint. Oh, I bet there's
another endpoint. I bet there's another
endpoint." And then maybe eventually
you'll hit a point where it's like,
"Okay, I haven't found anything in a
while. Um they've probably gone through
and done like a a manual check to
and or a manual review internally to
see, 'Okay, this
this has been a systemic issue. Let's
fix them all.'"
And then that'll kind of make me move
move targets. But um
I guess finding finding bugs continually
finding bugs is what keeps me keeps me
motivated. But but yeah, if I'm if I'm
not finding things, I'm not going to
just sit there and grind for 8, 10, 20
hours um just because there's a lot of
endpoints. Um unless they happen to pay
a lot for
for these types of bugs. And so um I can
talk more about specific programs that I
really enjoy for this. Um it's a public
program and so I
I'm fine talking about it, but I've had
a lot of fun uh hacking on GitHub. And
GitHub has a very complicated uh
permission structure. And they do a very
good job of validating permissions, but
when each when you know, when every
single medium severity privilege
escalation pays you like $4,000, that's
a
you know, that's
more than a lot of programs pay for
criticals. And so it's
I don't I don't mind grinding for
you know, for 5, 6, 7 hours to find a a
$4,000 medium because that's that's
worth it when it comes to
to my time. But obviously if it's a
smaller program and they're only paying
$500 for each
medium severity privilege escalation,
then
it's
I'm going to move on pretty fast if I'm
not finding stuff.
Yeah, from your perspective, are there
any patterns in what what types of
privilege escalations are usually
possible? Cuz for example, from my
perspective, when I had less experience,
I probably would skip at the deletion
endpoints. I would like think definitely
about the read endpoints. They were
quite obvious. About, you know, creating
endpoints, post, put endpoints. That
would probably like not really consider
the the delete endpoints. How does it
look from your perspective?
Yeah, I'd say there's been there's been
a number of times where I found a an
endpoint like the put endpoint is
protected, the get endpoint is
protected, but for some reason the the
delete endpoint hasn't been protected.
And so I will yeah, I will always always
check deletion as well. Um
what's been really interesting is when
uh like the put endpoint is protected,
but they also have a patch endpoint
which does the same thing.
Um and then you can kind of bypass a
protection on put by just doing patch
instead. And so those are I see that's
not very common, but when you find
something
find something like that, it's it's
pretty exciting and pretty cool.
Yeah.
I I also you said GitHub. I think GitHub
is also as much interesting that by
default you have the functionality of
pull requests. So different user have
some way to to interact with different
users.
Which um
I I think usually makes attack more more
likely because there is the attack
scenario of of you know, attacking a
user that's completely anonymous cuz
the other the other thing that's that I
wanted to ask you is about the the usual
risk cuz
often for to escalate privileges, we we
need to already have some privileges,
which
usually makes these these
vulnerabilities um
highs or or mediums or
maybe sometimes even lows.
Uh so what what what what do you think
and where should we look for for these
higher risk more more risky bugs?
Yeah, so
I'd say there that's a good question. Um
there privilege escalations can usually
get up to critical when they are
combined with when when there's also
like an IDOR vulnerability.
And so it might not be very critical if
like a read-only user of your own
company can
uh
you know, read confidential data, but if
there's also an IDOR there where a
read-only user from a company can can
read admin data from another
organization, then that's kind of going
to be what bumps it up to
bumps it up to critical.
Um or occasionally there will be like a
like an application that has like free
sign-up, but has a like
special elevated permissions for uh like
staff or um
or admins that's like specially granted.
I was just hacking on a on a program
recently where anybody can sign up and
use the application and create their own
org, but then there was also like
another layer of super users. And so,
that I don't know how they got their
permissions. Like some of them are are
staff or maybe they just have to like
apply and it's a
paid position. I don't know. But being
able to kind of cross that additional
boundary. So, yeah, you can be an admin
of your own org. So, what? But if you
can as an admin of your own org become a
super admin or do super admin abilities
to affect other orgs, then that's that's
going to be what what bumps up to
critical. But you're right in that that
most most privilege escalations that I
report are going to be medium or high
severity. Occasionally some lows. I wish
I was like Alex Chapman and you know,
just spat out criticals like
it was a you know, no big deal. But I
guess if you look at my my bug bounty
resume
most of my bugs are
or my my most submitted type of bug is
medium
followed by like highs and lows are kind
of the same. And then criticals are
are
much lower.
Yeah, but on the other hand I think you
submit way way more bugs. And it's also
some a good way to differentiate
yourself cuz I feel like
it's it's very cool to say let's say in
an interview like this that that someone
only looks for for critical bugs which
Alex is a very very specific case. Let's
let's put it aside cuz he's he looks for
very very specific types of bugs.
But a lot of people say that they they
focus on on highs and and criticals and
the thing is when you say me that you
submit
you know, you you find a bug every half
an hour 1 hour 1 and half 1 and half
hour
you I imagine you just have a big volume
of of reports and that's that's what
generates the the money and
that's also just a different way to to
to earn the same salary potentially.
Right. Right.
Um
Yeah, and it helps that I look at I look
at smaller programs mostly.
Most of my time is spent on smaller
programs that don't pay as much but are
are generally more vulnerable. And so, I
I'll say
last week I think I submitted
five or six or seven
vulnerabilities. Whereas, you know,
someone
who is only focused on focuses on
criticals might
submit one bug every two weeks and then
you know, make like $15,000 per
per bug that they you know, report. And
that's that's just not me. Most of my
most of my crits are $3,000 crits.
How do you write reports cuz I imagine
for with with this
style you spend much more time writing
reports. So, what do you do to make to
make it as quick as possible?
You know, I've heard of hackers who use
like ChatGPT to write reports for them.
I haven't gotten to that level of
automation. I think it's really cool and
I probably should. HackerOne recently
introduced
I guess maybe last year introduced
templates. And so, you can if you report
one specific type of vulnerability
then
like say you're just report a lot of XSS
and you can just like use a template and
replace the values with like the
endpoint and the payload.
Again, I
this is probably a
my Achilles heel. I I think this is a an
underutilized area for me that I could
definitely improve on because I I do
just manually manually write all of my
reports and I try to be clear and I try
to just list out the steps very like
concisely and
it's worked. But yeah, I think now that
I'm moving full-time I'm very open to
change and open to improvements. And I
think this is going to be one of those
key
key skills that I have not developed
that needs to be developed.
Yeah, although with with the templates
on HackerOne
I think I I imagine triagers have seen
these templates so many times already
that they just skip through any text
that's there and can probably
you know, say it from from their memory.
So, I don't know. Personally I don't use
it as well. My reports are often quite
short these days and
yeah, I don't know about ChatGPT. I know
that a few days ago Justin Rhinehart
released some tool that uses ChatGPT
or AI in general to generate reports. I
haven't I haven't tested it yet. Maybe
that's the way. But
yeah, for me as well I just do manually
and
and I think if you're concise it doesn't
take as as much time. But we'll see.
It definitely makes it quicker.
I I did have an interesting experience
recently where I was writing a report
for a just a pen test I was doing just
like for consulting work. So, no
relation to bug bounty at all. They had
just paid me to
to take a look at some web applications
and and write reports. And it dawned on
me that like how much I take for granted
that
uh
triage teams whether they're HackerOne's
triage or the program's triage
typically know
enough about security to be able to
parse just a very concise report.
Whereas, when I'm writing this
when I'm writing this report for a
like what was effectively the the CISO
and you know, maybe like the director of
engineering. Like these are
less technical but still very
influential roles that I had to kind of
change how I was writing my report.
Like I couldn't just say there's an XSS
on this endpoint. You know, which I
where I might do in in like a HackerOne
report. I had to say
okay, if you go to this endpoint as this
type of user and you do this payload
it'll show an alert box. However, with
XSS it's not just about
and you know, it's not just about
showing an alert box. This effectively
gives the attacker control over the
JavaScript in the the victim's the
victim's browser and is it you know,
basically browser takeover. And so, I
had kind of had to explain like the
impact a bit differently
just because I wasn't going through a
bug bounty platform. And that was a
really really unique experience. And so,
writing reports took me a fair bit
longer because I was just having to
to to write them differently and be more
you know, explain the context and the
the impact of of vulnerabilities a bit
more.
Yeah, yeah, we spoke about exactly the
same thing with Alex cuz
me as well as a pen tester I was used to
writing these these reports you know, to
developers that maybe have not heard
about a particular vulnerability class.
And so, the report had the explanation
of of what happens. And then when when
doing bug bounties I would just you
know, default to doing the same. And
only only now with with some experience
I I get to realize I don't need to do
this anymore.
Right. Right. And my And my experience
is like the opposite, right? Cuz I
started in like doing bug bounty or just
writing you know, really short you know,
three line reports. Like hey there,
there's an XSS on this endpoint. Go here
and you'll see the see the alert
payload. Whereas, if I'm delivering like
a pen test report I can't do that. I
have to say I have to explain
what? Like the I have to explain the
impact more rather than just trusting
triage to understand the impact. And so,
I kind of had to rather than shortening
my reports I had to make them longer in
a in a pen test.
Yeah, yeah, but
at least I imagine this as you doing
them as a freelancer I imagine you you
have the freedom of choosing the format.
After when you work in a company I have
to do it in Microsoft Word and keep the
template and it always breaks and it is
just horrible. Yeah.
And I remember I was trying to automate
generating
reports for docx. It was just horrible
experience. Oh.
Yeah, that's that's terrible. I just
make a make a markdown file in Obsidian
and convert to PDF and then send it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's that's what I
do as well. Well, but my case
notion. But yeah, but speaking of of of
noting programs when you want to be more
meticulous and you want to note
the the permissions and and what you've
checked and what you're going to check.
How does does exactly your noting style
look like?
Yeah, so I'll I'll typically just use a
just pull up like an Obsidian like file
and I won't structure it in any way. But
if there's like an endpoint that I want
to check I'll just copy and paste it
there and I'll typically remember what
the context is around that around that
endpoint. If there's a
a UUID that I need to test and I want to
like save it somewhere I'll slap it into
into the you know, the markdown file. If
there's a just like user IDs or order
IDs or any type of ID just like put it
there. And then I might make like a
little note that says like admin ID or
read only ID. Um and just kind of just
keep basically use it as like a
scratchpad
just so that I don't have to like
remember remember numbers or or remember
endpoints. And so, it's not it's not
super mature. It's not like I'm saying
all right, I tested this and this this
this and this and now I'm going to
you know, tomorrow I'm going to modify
my modify my testing approach by
looking for this type of vulnerability
on this type of functionality. And so, I
use it more just as I as I would like a
piece of pen and paper when I'm
basically just hold this information so
I don't have to have it in my brain
while I do some testing and then I'll
pull it back later.
Yeah, and and more specifically when
you're already testing do you
do you have any organized way you
you keep cookies for one user cookies
for a different user? Do you use
repeater tabs? How does it look like?
Cuz also yesterday when I was I was
testing it. It It sounds like something
easy to handle, but it was also like how
this cookie does no longer work. I
forgot from which user was this cookie
and there's a lot of problems like this.
So, if I if I had Caido up Sorry, I use
Caido, but if you're using Burp Suite or
whatever, but I had it up just this
morning and I think I had somewhere
around like 200 tabs
and
usually not use most of those old ones,
but what I do is say say I'm looking at
an application and there's two types of
users, right? There's like low-level
user and admin user and I want to test
for privilege escalations. I'll make a
single request with like my lower-level
user,
send it to the repeater and just rename
the tab uh lower user or lesser user or
whatever and I'll just keep that keep
that tab there. And then I'll go through
as an admin user, just look at all the
endpoints and send them all to the
repeater.
And so I've got, you know, my first tab
is lower user and then I've got like
maybe like after testing like a or just
going through like one piece of
functionality, I might see like 10 10
tabs that are after that which were all
made by the admin. And I'll just start
from the latest, grab the endpoint,
paste it into the into the uh lesser
user tab, uh try that. If it doesn't
work, then I'll close that uh
close that admin tab, move to the next.
If it does work, I'll rename the tab to
bug. So, I'll just change it and write
bug so that I remember there's a bug
there. Then I'll move to the next one,
try it. If
change the tab name to bug and then uh
uh if not, I'll just delete that delete
that tab. And then once I've got a bunch
of bugs like bug tabs, I'll go through
and I'm ready to report, I'll go through
and report and then change the change
the tab name from bug to reported so
that I know that I I've reported it. And
that's just kind of how I keep track of
okay, here's the
here's the the different privilege
escalations that that worked um and
here's
here's um
the ones I've reported so that I don't
uh forget something.
Yeah, that's cool.
yeah, it's pretty it's pretty
rudimentary, but it it works for me.
There might be a more mature way to do
it, but I really it's it's worked really
well just using just using tabs as my as
my organization structure.
Yeah, I wish I also started using Caido.
I wish there was a feature like in
Postman. I don't know if you ever used
Postman, but then you can sort of define
on the collection level variables like
cookies, authorization headers, some
variables.
I wish there was a feature like this and
I could have like a set of let's say
this is UUID of some item in admin that
I shouldn't access with a low-privilege
user, one place where I could just
change the cookies and stuff like this.
I feel like this would be this would be
a killer feature if they had it.
That would be Yeah, that would be super
cool. I know that the the Caido team has
been really good I mean, this I don't
think this is sponsored by Caido, but
it's all right by me talking about it.
Um No, we can talk about it. It's It's
It's great. I really like it. I started
using like like months ago and and I
really like it. So, we we if we like it,
we should do the the best job to promote
it.
Oh, for sure. Yeah, definitely. They and
the team is very responsive to to any
bugs or feature requests. And so they've
Yeah, if you I might, you know, either
you or I should make that a make that a
feature request in
in their GitHub repository cuz they're
generally pretty responsive and the team
is really great to work with.
Yeah.
Uh also, what's your browser set up for
multiple tabs? I imagine with two users
you can just use the normal tab and the
incognito tab, but what happens if there
are let's say three different roles?
Yeah, so that's a good question.
So, I I use Firefox and I will have
typically one type of user in my Firefox
and then I'll open an incognito, have
another type of user. If I happen to
have to go to three, then I'll open up
Chrome and I've got Chrome configured to
go through
its reverse proxy as well. Um but that's
that's less common or I'll just try
everything with my incognito tab user,
close that out, reopen it and then try
it try it with uh
the the third type of user. But yes, to
I generally just test two types of uh
users at a time. Um just one in
Firefox and the other in an incognito
and then, you know, also in in Firefox.
Yeah. Yeah, okay, that's that's a simple
solution.
Mhm.
What case would you do?
and and part of this
I do I know there is I think for Firefox
there is like tab colorizer, something
like this.
And then you can uh I don't know they
just don't use Firefox.
Um
Some I use the the Chrome profiles. So,
when I use Chrome, I have different
profiles for different users.
And in Burp when I can I use Burp, I
also had different user agents for them
and different colors in Burp for these
requests.
So, it's really nice, but now in in
Caido I just do
um I just did did basically the same. I
just did the normal window and the
incognito incognito window and for two
users it was it was enough.
Definitely. Definitely. Yeah, that's
similar to me.
Uh do you automate any part of the of
the process?
No, and I really should, man.
I
I see so many audit like automation
hackers and they're just able to crush
it and I I'm stuck in this situation
where it's like there's a learning curve
to implementing like automation type
solutions. Um but now that this is my
full-time job, anytime that I'm not
hacking and
in the way that I know best is
you know, costs me and so it's like oh,
do I want to take Do I want to take a
week
where I'm going to effectively most
likely be making no money because I'm
not I'm not hacking the way that I know
how to hack to learn a new skill set
which is
probably going to make me make me more
money in the long run, but it's just,
you know, scary making that making that
decision to
to invest that invest the time when
uh
you know, I try to keep up uh
some bounty quotas to be able to
to just keep my keep my lifestyle and
and invest in the things I want to
invest. So, it's
I'm sure that
that'll that'll come with time. Um but
yeah, there's so many so many things I'd
love to I'd love to automate whether
it's just having like a good fuzzing set
up where
uh cuz I feel like there's there's
hackers that are finding easy easy
vulnerabilities that I'm just not
finding because they're able to, you
know, find endpoints that um I'm you
know, just don't show up in the UI,
right? Like they might find like an
actuator endpoint which they're able to,
you know, restart or shut down the
entire application. And it's like that's
awesome. That's a critical that I'm not
going to find because I'm not scanning
for it. And so, there's so many cool so
many cool ways to to improve. It's just
a matter of taking the time to
to pull the trigger and
I'm getting there, but I'm not I'm not
going to pretend to be the the world's
best hacker.
Yeah, yeah, I know exactly what what you
mean with investing time cuz I I
recorded an interview with with Joe with
Technogeek a few days a few days ago
and he he does mobile hacking a lot and
and so I was like yeah, let's try. So, I
spent like two days two two full days of
work trying to bypass SSL pinning of a
mobile app and I still didn't do it.
Felt like
Yeah. Oh my god, it felt so bad, but
then
but with automation I feel like
know that there are vulnerabilities
there. Yeah, yeah, 100%. It is the the
customer of the H1702. I don't know if
the mobile app would be in scope, but I
was I wanted to just, you know, make a
head start to do it a little bit
earlier.
But with with automation, I think this
is so far off what would I what I want
to do that it's not even tempting to me
to to try. Oh, yeah.
But for you, uh
I wanted to ask if you are thinking
about automating like the the things
that usually these hackers automate like
you mentioned actuator
or you would like to somehow automate
testing for for the privilege
escalations for for your bread and
butter, basically?
Yeah, that's a that's a good question. I
think the
uh so, when I look at the
the really heavy automation hackers, I
feel like the things that they are
successful with are things like
subdomain takeovers and are finding like
in asset discovery, like maybe finding
some endpoint that or some uh
like old service that's running on some
obscure subdomain that contains like
business-critical information. And so,
that's I guess that's probably the most
attractive to me.
I could try to like come up with a
automation automation solution to to
test my bread and butter, but then I
feel like it would stop being my bread
and butter.
Like I feel like I'm I'm very good at
finding these privilege escalations and
IDORs.
And I kind of
would like to keep keep doing that
because it's fun.
Um And so, if I can throw in some
automation to find stuff that isn't as
fun for me to
to hack, then maybe that's the maybe
that's the key. You know, going through
and like looking at looking at various
subdomains and doing like
clicking on every single subdomain that
shows up in like Shodan, you know, it's
it's pretty tedious work and it's not
very exciting to me, but if I can have
automation to do that for me, then I've
kind of got
I've got my blind spot covered.
Yeah. Yeah, okay, I see.
Yeah, this this What but also
one thing that I I noticed in in these
interviews is that
everyone from the top has just is good
at
uh at ignoring parts that they are not
good at and
like let's say Alex is is ignoring the
the web parts of the application,
basically.
Uh
other people have just, you know, they
they're vulnerability class. So, uh
when I I feel less and less the the need
to do everything. Sometimes when
especially like
maybe now even in the in the Ambassador
World Cup when we did a little bit more
collaborations, I saw a lot of this guy
does this or why what does that guy does
that and I'm like never doing these
things. I'm like oh I should probably do
more.
But then you know it's it's still good
to to to keep something that's that that
you're a specialist at and just ignore
all the rest.
It it's funny that you bring up Alex and
collaboration and maybe this is a good a
good segue into a a collaboration
discussion. Um but collabing with Alex,
I've done it a number of times. It's
it's always a really cool experience
because we are just such like such
different hackers. And so we'll I'll be
like working with him on a on a live
event and
you know, from his perspective he'll go
to sleep and then he'll wake up with you
nine collaboration like invites. He's
like what how how you found nine bugs
while I was sleeping? And I'm like yeah,
but they're you know, just all privilege
escalations or they're all IDORs or or
all whatever.
Um and then from my perspective, you
know, I'll be like
the only one finding bugs for a couple
days and then suddenly like an internet
breaking vulnerability like show up in
my in my inbox and I'll read through it
and have to like read through it seven
or eight times and be like goodness, how
did you find how how on earth did you
find this? And he's like oh you know, I
just I just went down a rabbit trail and
and didn't uh
uh didn't sleep much, but you know,
here's this
way that I can you
steal any website on the internet. I'm
like goodness gracious, dude. That's
that's amazing. And so it's it's really
it's really fun collabing with Alex just
because we hack in such different ways
that I know I know we don't have any
crossover. Like I'll I'll collab with
with people who are also like web app
hackers and
are really good at finding IDORs and
privilege escalations and a lot of the
reports we I'll find or they'll find has
been
like oh I should have found that or like
oh yeah, I would have found that when I
when I uh
uh when I eventually got to that piece
of functionality. And so collabing with
them just allows for
more surface area. You know, we're
basically acting as the same person just
testing two different apps at the same
time or two different pieces of
functionality at the same time. But test
a hacking and collabing with Alex is
just something completely different
because we're we're just hacking on two
different like two different planes. Um
I'm finding vulnerabilities that he's
never going to look for um because you
know, they they aren't as interesting to
his uh you know, wizard brain and he's
finding things that I would lose
patience testing for like
um days or you know, hours or days
before
uh before he does. And so he'll like get
hooked on something and and know there's
a vulnerability there and spend
days working on it and eventually it'll
you know, come to fruition. And I'll
I'll have like moved on days before him.
And so because of that, I don't feel
like there's really any overlap and Alex
and I can look at the same web page and
the same piece of functionality and find
completely different bugs
because we're just two different
hackers.
Yeah. Yeah, if if
I were to find two most distinct hacking
styles of anyone that I know, I think
you two are the perfect example.
I think it's like it's it's as far away
as as it's possible. So how do you then
what's your model of collaboration then
and what's the reason of the
collaboration then?
So collaboration for me is first and
foremost, I think it makes it fun. Like
bug bounty is a lonely world. You're
working by yourself all the time
typically.
Um
and it's just it's it's so much more fun
to
like share ideas and share
vulnerabilities that you find with
people especially when
you know, vulnerabilities that you find
are also going to get you paid. And so
it's less about like trying to min-max
and find like the perfect team to be
able to find every single type type of
vulnerability on an application to get
the most amount of money and it's more
about who who am I going to want to be
chatting with on Discord or Slack for
you know, eight hours a day for two
weeks. And it's going to be the people
that who are just cool to work with and
who are are fun and easygoing and
and you know, I
typically will know what they're doing,
but for the most part it's like who who
do I want to be my coworker right now?
And that's kind of how I choose my
choose my collaborations. It's it's
people that I just enjoy enjoy working
with.
And
uh yeah, and so typically before like
before a live event, I'll
um I haven't been doing this recently
because I've been kind of wanting to go
out on my on my own this year and see
how I can do on live events, but
historically what I've done is before a
live event we'll start before we even
know the scope
um or occasionally after we know the
scope, I'll just reach out to you know,
this person and this person and this
person and say hey,
do you guys want to team up for this for
this live event? And you know, most
people are really excited to team up
because it's just it's fun. You know,
I'm getting on a getting on a call like
on Zoom or
or Discord or or whatever and across
time zones and just looking at stuff at
the same time like on a call is
I mean it's it's it's the best type of
hacking. It's there's there's nothing
that beats it because when you when
you're
I I guess being in person beats it, but
when you're looking at something with
the same time and you find a
vulnerability with someone and they're
on a call with you and you can both like
react at the same time be like oh oh,
you know, we're able to
we're already able to you know, escalate
to admin. Can we escalate to super
admin? Oh it works. Oh this is so
awesome. And you know, they're like
right there with you. It's
yeah it just not nothing beats it. And
so it's it's about it's about fun. Um
that's that's pretty much why I why I
collab.
Yeah and then so the model of this is
you just agree to to team up for the
live hacking event and and you split all
the bounties equally. Is that that's
right? Yeah.
That's the way to do it. Um I've heard
of people getting burnt and not you
know, having somebody on their team who
just doesn't collaborate and doesn't
um
you know, doesn't pull their weight and
I don't I don't know. I feel like once
you once you're at the level where
you're going to live events, um
you know, ev- everybody who gets invited
to a live event knows what they're
doing. You're not going to and hopefully
everybody who goes to a live event
especially if they've been to multiple
aren't just there to
to make some quick cash and
uh
you know, be a jerk. Like people people
are at these live events because they
love hacking and they love the hacker
community. And the last thing that they
want to do is to
you know, create bad blood between two
hackers. And so I haven't
I I've been like the under contributor
um on some events.
Um
and I've been the over contributor on
some events. And I think it kind of
even especially if you collab as a team
over you know, multiple multiple events.
You know, maybe if you collab with
someone multiple times in a row and they
just don't part you know, contribute,
then you can just stop collabing with
them on future events, but I don't know.
I think
I I think it would be kind of petty to
to give somebody a hard time especially
if they were trying because they didn't
you know, find vulnerabilities or
because you found more than them. It's
just like
I mean this is this is bug bounty that
we all we all like the game. We all like
the community. It's it's way more fun to
just
you know, just work together and
and enjoy the experience than
squabble over this person
you know, cost me $3,000 in in bounties
because they you know, didn't find as
much as as me. It's like you know,
whatever.
Um I was actually just talking to
another hacker uh I was talking to
Michael 1026 who had
who had done a collab and uh
and they they with somebody and and we
were talking about how weird it is that
in bug bounty
the money almost doesn't feel real. Like
it feels like Monopoly money when you
can just be like oh um yeah, I'll go
ahead and give you you know, 30% because
you
told me about some endpoint that I
wouldn't have otherwise discovered. When
like in reality, you know, 30% might be
$3,000 on a $10,000 bounty. And so
you're just casually saying yeah, you
can have $3,000 for helping me. Like in
what other industry do people like so
like
frivolously just throw throw around
money in in collaborations. It's it's
it's really unique.
Yeah. Yeah, it's fun.
Have you ever got to a point where you
had let's say a difficult conversation
with somebody that let's say you
collabed in the past and then you
decided you you you don't want to collab
with this person?
Um I've had I've had moments where I've
reached out to somebody and said like
hey, like they maybe maybe they reached
out wanting to collab and I had to say
like I'm actually going to go solo this
event or I'm actually going to work with
these people this event. Um
whether or not that was because they
contri- you know, under contributed in
in a previous event or
uh because I just really wanted to try
collaborating with these new people. Um
you know, I've
had both.
Um
but I see that's kind of the the closest
or the the most
the most difficult conversation I've had
is just saying like no, I'd I'd rather
not collab this event after somebody
reached uh reached out. Um
I've uh yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, how how does the
collaboration model look like for
Ambassador World Cup cuz you're also an
ambassador for the US team.
There it's it's a way bigger group and
and also I assume that everyone spends
as much time. Not everyone is uh
uh as you said, for the live hacking
event the the group is is is pretty
pretty selective. For the World Cup it's
it changes how does the collaboration
model look like there?
Yeah, so
I think there there lots of people are
collaborating with in our team and I
think typically it's because they
like they we know each other's skill
set. I had um
uh Stealthy reach out to me
um about a particular asset because he
knows I'm really good at at privilege
escalations and permission bugs. And so
he's like, "Hey, I found this
I found this
this particular application which I
don't think anybody else has discovered
yet. It looks like it's got a a
complicated permission structure. I'm
going to invite you to it and you know,
any bugs you find we'll just we'll
split." Uh
and so yeah, I was able to
surprisingly I didn't actually find any
permission bugs, but I found a number of
XSS. But um we still yeah, any bugs that
we found on that application we we split
together and it was just because he knew
that I was good at at privilege
escalations and I mean similarly if I
find something that
looks like it might be vulnerable to
request smuggling or or
RCE then I kind of throw it his
direction.
And then you know, NahamSec is really
really good at blind XSS and so if
there's help I need with a blind XSS
then
um then I reach out to him. Um Ziyad on
our team is also very good at at XSS
particularly like bypassing uh filters.
Um
And so yeah, we just we just kind of
know what each other's skill sets are
and and reach out on a I guess per need
basis within within the World Cup. So
it's less it's less like a a traditional
life hacking event in that we're not
like
teaming up to split bounties. It's just
oh, I need I need somebody with this
skill set on this asset here. Let's
let's collab.
Um
But the cool thing about the World Cup
is that
we still get excited when the rest of
our team finds uh
finds bugs and gets bounties because it
means our team gets points. And so
that's kind of a a nice thing. Like I'd
hear about two hackers finding something
super cool and I'm not getting any money
for you know, for it because I wasn't
you know, I wasn't helping. But I'm also
happy because oh, that means you know,
our team got was like 26 points for
being you know, if it's a critical it's
like awesome. Yeah, I mean our our
likelihood of advancing to the next
round is much higher now because you two
were collaborating and as a bonus you
both got a bunch of money. So
Yeah, yeah, that's so cool. That's
that's good as what what you said for
somebody finds something interesting
they post it and like everyone is happy
and it's it's like crazy bugs as well
because with with bigger group it's also
naturally more bugs.
So yeah, for for me the the the closest
to to to what you said cuz I've never
been this sort of team collab, but most
collabs that I did were like you said
per need basis where either somebody
would reach out to me or I would reach
out to somebody or I would reach out to
some automation hackers to scale the
zero day.
And uh yeah, so the the
uh
I I see that that for you this is just
what you're doing the World Cup.
Yeah, yeah, and your team I looked at
the leaderboards like Poland
really crushed it uh this this first
round. So
we we might
Yeah, we might be going I think we're
fourth. So we might be going head to
head in a in a future round.
Yeah, yeah, we don't know if we don't
know if we made the group stage yet.
Right now in the group stage. So maybe
we'll go head to head in in person if we
both make it to the the round of eight.
Let's hope we meet in the final I think
I say.
Yeah, there we go.
Yeah.
Now we just need to stage the drawing,
but that that's easily hackable.
Uh I will go back a little bit to to the
hacking part cuz I have
a few questions that that are really
bothering me and and I I kind of
overlooked them.
Um
You find a lot of bugs and
some of them I imagine have uh the
company respond to you, you know, this
is a single fix for all of these bugs
and we close all of them as as
duplicates. Does it happen often?
Yeah, yeah, so there's a whole meta game
around this, right? Like this especially
when you're when you're first couple
reports to a program and you don't know
it very well, you're going to have two
paths to go. Like let's say you find two
really similar vulnerabilities.
You can take the the approach where
you're going to submit them both cuz
they're say they're say they're two
separate endpoints, but they're the same
impact, right? Like it's a
say it's like an XSS on you know,
endpoint one and an XSS on endpoint two.
You submit them both
and
and like you really hope and push for
them to be treated separately, but that
risks them being closed as duplicate.
On the other hand you can submit a one
then hope that they don't also look and
find it on the second endpoint and then
report it again which if you you know,
they fix the first one and then you
report the second one they can't say
it's a duplicate because obviously they
fixed one but not the other. And so it's
a it's a real like gamble and this kind
of it's kind of makes the the whole game
fun, right? Um but I think as you as you
get to know a program um
you kind of know what their what their
stance is on duplicates and how they how
they treat duplicates. But to be safe
what I love is when I can find a like a
third endpoint which is not vulnerable
so that I can prove that these cannot be
dupes because like let's say you have
endpoints A, B, and C
and A and C are vulnerable, but endpoint
B is not vulnerable then you can submit
both A and C and then like in a note in
them say, "This is not a dupe A is not a
duplicate of C because
clearly B is being handled in a in a
completely different way. And so these
are these are being uh
the fix the fixes need to be individual
because otherwise if these if A and C
were duplicates then B would also be
vulnerable." And so if you can find a
uh if you can find a a third endpoint
that's really helpful. Uh what also I'll
do is kind of on a similar vein is if I
find a a concrete example with with some
imaginary app of of this situation where
you have
two endpoints and then the third one
that you could use to to to prove that
it's not a dupe with like a real
functionality to so the viewers get the
better better image of what do you mean?
Yeah, sure sure.
Yeah, so let's say let's say you've got
an application and it's a like a
document application which lets you like
upload upload documents. Um and let's
say that you find an XSS in
the document name. And so like you can
like upload a document with a malicious
like title and it fires on other users.
You also find that if your username
um
is has a XSS payload it also has an XSS
in you. It also like fires on users.
But on that same page where those are
both vulnerable, let's say that there's
a like a document description field
which you try doing an XSS and it's not
vulnerable. Then you can say, "Look,
this is not a single fix on this page
because you're doing you're sanitizing
the
the document description and so it's not
vulnerable, but the username and the
title of the document are vulnerable.
And so you can't say that these are
these are one fix because you've got
this third thing where
it's already fixed. So is that I'm not
sure if that if that helps.
Yeah, yeah, it does. Thank you. How
would you define a duplicate then? Like
also you have the experience from the
other side of the program.
When is duplicate a duplicate? Is it a
single fix that's the consist?
Yeah, so historically that's that's what
it I mean that's that's what it
is officially and that's what it should
be. Um
like if if it's a single like line of
code and you make one change then
and it fixes it in multiple locations
then obviously that's that's a dupe.
Um
I what where it gets dicey is what some
companies will do is
they'll be like it'll be one fix, but
you need to apply it multiple places.
And so it might like you might need to
it might be one page that's vulnerable
and the fix is the same on each on each
on each vulnerable page.
But you're going to have to like be
fixing multiple files. And so you can
put in a fix for you know, for for page
one
and then push the change and it'll be
fixed, but it won't be fixed for change
two.
However, they might be like, "Oh no, we
just have to put the same change in you
know, page two, page three, page four
and they'll all get fixed." And they'll
call that one fix. It's like, "No, it's
one solution for multiple problems."
But they are they are all individual
fixes. And so it's you know, this has
been you know, this this uh
discussion is like tale as old as time,
right? Like we've been arguing this with
with programs for for years.
And I think it's just going to come down
to the maturity of the maturity of the
program. Um
and
yeah, ultimately at the end of the day
bug bounty works because programs
want to run bug bounty programs and
so the
the final say is always going to land on
the program, but I think that we can you
make a pretty solid case when
you're looking at something that's
two separate you know, clearly two
separate issues. I an an another area
where it might get dicey is when you've
got like a systemic issue and they're
like, "Okay,
we're not checking we're not
we're not doing any authorization checks
at all. It's all client side. And so any
type of user can hit every single
endpoint."
And it's like, "Okay, is there's you
know, 65 different endpoints. Is that 65
different bugs?" It's like
uh
even as a hacker I'd have a hard time
like saying like, "Yeah, there's 65
different bugs because it's you know, 65
different endpoints when the bug is that
there's just no authorization structure
at all. And so, you know, maybe I I
think in those in that case I'd be like,
okay, this is like one like max
critical, but you know, pay as a max
critical.
But sure, if you if you need to like if
the solution is just a completely like a
complete re-architecture of how you're
doing your permission structure, then
um then sure, I'm fine with it being one
fix, but it better be paid you
appropriately.
So, how would you report it if if let's
say there was no authorization at all?
And let's say you have
20 vulnerable endpoints. What do you do?
And and it's a fresh program and you
have no track record with them.
Yeah, um
so, what I what I would if it's yeah,
that's a good uh addendum. Um if I if
it's a fresh program and I have no uh
track record with them, what I would do
is I would report them all individually
and then with a note on at the bottom of
each one that says, if these are like
one fix, please adjust the severity
accordingly. And so, I might file like
20 mediums. Um
but if they are going to get duped
together, I want there to be a note in
every single one that says, this if this
is a single fix, this is absolutely a
you know, a a critical. So, cuz the last
thing you want is for like 20 mediums to
be duped into one medium. It's like, no,
it's not a medium then. It was
a massive
massive problem. So, uh and I actually
did that a a while back
in
uh what I did this twice.
So, I had one program. It's my my number
one program um that I've filed the most
bugs on.
And I had a
a pretty big
architectural issue and I reported it as
all separate endpoints.
They duped them all.
And they did increase the severity to
critical. And so, I found a couple like
I think a
year later I found another thing. And it
was like
they had like a reporting feature where
you could like generate reports admins
could like generate reports,
you know, about the data in their
organization like, you know, all users
and all documents, etc. Um
and every single type of report
was vulnerable to privilege escalation
where a user that had access to no data
could or very little data could
basically get every every bit of
information by running every single type
of report. And so, because I had that
track record in the past, I just like
made a note at the very top all caps,
note to triage,
I am this is actually 15 different
vulnerabilities. I am filing them as one
as one critical. You know, you know,
treat this please don't downgrade this
when you know, because you're just like
checking the CVSS box. And so, I'm like,
okay. And so, they yeah, the the team
handled it as a critical and they were
very appreciative that I didn't give
them 15 different you know, 15 different
reports. They're just like
they're like, yep, it's one one holistic
fix. There's no there's no authorization
on this reporting
uh reporting issue or report on these
reporting endpoints.
And yeah, I got my credit.
Yeah, I wish we as bug hunters we we had
a way to know these things before
interacting with a program. Let's let's
say you have a program
somehow defines very clear rules about
things like these duplicates like maybe
they they want you to submit one report
and and they will increase this maybe
maybe reward a bonus for each vulnerable
endpoint, something like this. Yeah,
yeah. Um because it it it's it's
it's painful that for things like that
for let's say reporting zero days as
well, usually we have zero knowledge
about what programs do with these and
and especially if you are to to submit
like 20 reports, that's a lot of work
just submitting these reports.
Yeah.
It's it sucks if this this gets you
know, duplicated into one and and it
just adds work to to everyone.
Yeah, it does. It does. And I think that
that's a really big draw to these bigger
mature programs that have like a a big
track record like like
uh Amazon or Shopify or GitHub or Yahoo
or PayPal or you know, what whatever
because they typically have matured to
the point where they have policies that
are
pretty reliable. And if you find that
they are deviating from their typical
behavior, you can point them back at old
reports whether by reported by you or
just disclose reports and say, no,
actually it looks like, you know, you're
you treated this one as an individual
report instead of a dupe, then therefore
can you look at at this one instead. And
they're
generally pretty open to to
you know, siding with you. Whereas if
you have a brand new program who's like
might still be kind of like wary of
hackers and see us as as adversaries,
you might have a harder time getting
them to
be a bit more liberal with their with
their budget.
Yeah.
Yeah, and another let's say
bounty long discussion about the is it a
bug is it not a bug? Uh you IDs, what
happens if if your bug requires attacker
to know the the UUID?
Right. So, so UUIDs, I mean I I will say
UUIDs should absolutely be considered
like valid vulnerabilities just with the
attack scenario set to high or attack
complexity set to high because it is
very you know, because people leave
organizations, right? Like you may not
be able to like brute force a UUID, but
if you have an employee who like leaves
your organization, like they
and they like wrote down what their you
know, user UUID is, then they can
then they can still affect you know,
still affect your company
post-termination. Um
additionally, there have been a number
of times where I've found oracles that
basically render UUIDs uh useless. Like
I was hacking on a this was a couple
years ago and I was hacking on an
application and every single ID was a
UUID, right? So, they're probably
feeling really good about their security
like there's no way you can brute force
these UUIDs.
Um but there was one endpoint
one endpoint that leaked every single
organization in the in the application
along with their UUID.
And so, if I had the organization's
UUID, then I could go and hit the
endpoint that requires the organization
UUID and then returns all user UUIDs.
And then now that I had the user's
UUIDs, I could then like modify other
users or I could modify their documents
or get a list of their documents, which
would then have the document UUID. And
so, basically I had this cascading
effect where just by that one endpoint
being able to see every single
organization's UUID
I could uh
it the fact that it was UUID at all, it
didn't matter because I could use that
UUID to get any other UUID in this
entire application.
And so, it was a that was a very very
lucrative uh HackerOne challenge for me.
Yeah, yeah. I think Uber for a long time
just treated UUIDs the prevention from
others. And I remember a blog post where
there was an endpoint where you would
just send the the email of the user and
the error that that would go back would
not have the email, but it would have
the UUID. Let's say user with UUID this
does not exist and and then the the
whole security was was just broken.
Yeah, that's exactly yeah, exactly
exactly that. Um same same thing. And
so, yeah, you cannot you cannot rely on
UUIDs because if a if a UUID leak exists
and they're they're common like they're
it it is there are oracles out there
that just get you any type of UUID you
need, then yeah, then your your security
is just going to be is just going to be
broken.
And so, I think in cases where
there's no way to attain the UUID like
in order you don't have an oracle or
whatever, then it should still be valid
just I always expect the attack
complexity to be set to high. Um and
that's kind of the way the way that I
think programs
uh programs need to treat it.
Yeah, I think since a few months at
least HackerOne has guidelines where it
literally it literally says it should be
like this.
Um so, so I guess if if somebody of of
viewers reports an ID or a privilege
escalation that requires a UUID on
HackerOne, just refer to the HackerOne
guidelines to to you know, make your
argument that much stronger.
Exactly. And you don't have to worry
about the triage team just shutting it
down before it even gets to the eyes of
eyes of the program. Yes, you know, if
the HackerOne policy says this or
guideline says this, then the triagers
are going to follow that.
Yeah.
Yeah, you also I know from different
interviews you like to to read
documentation and and to maybe catch
catch some words in the documentation
and use this to argue about some
vulnerabilities. What are some
surprising bugs that you found that
normally maybe you wouldn't report them,
but the documentation clearly would
would say that this should not be
possible and then still got paid for it.
Yeah, I'm going to have a I'm going to
have a hard time thinking of a specific
example, but I know that there there
have been a number of times on GitHub
specifically that I've reported issues
where like the the documentation might
say like
this endpoint works on issues, but not
pull like this a user should be able to
can do this on issues, but not pull
requests. And then I've been able to
find a way to do it on pull requests
because like internally issues and pull
requests are the exact same thing. Like
they're the exact same data type.
They're just
two types of of an of an issue. Like a a
is an issue. And so, that's been I found
a number of I've I think I report like
two of them have been turned into CVEs,
but there's been a number of of issues I
found
where a user can affect like pull
requests, uh
but not issues or or vice versa or
affect both of them when they when the
documentation says, "This only works on
issues. Does not work on pull requests."
And then, oh, here's a way to to get get
the tour come pull requests.
Yeah.
And Yeah, GitHub is I think GitHub is
very very special also because the the
hashes they work sort of the same hash
works on different repositories. So,
even if you have a fork and you are on
the main repository, you use the hash of
a fork, it also works. I don't know if
if issues and pull requests also share
the same logic, but I think GitHub is
very very special
Oh, that's interesting. I didn't know
that.
Yeah. Yeah, that's super cool.
So, all that say, documentation is
awesome and it is it is my best friend,
especially when arguing like the
validity of a bug because they can't say
if you can point to the documentation
put it like a square around it with a
couple of arrows that point to it, you
you're like, "You cannot tell me that
this is not a bug because the
documentation says this is a bug." And
then, they have their Occasionally,
you'll have a program that's like, "Oh,
our documentation needs to be updated."
But, it's like, "Okay."
Uh typically, they'll still pay for
that. Like, I know that
I think Salesforce pays for
documentation bugs. Um
Or yeah, or at least they did on the
their most uh most recent uh live event
where it was if they if there was
something that was wrong in the
documentation, then they would still pay
you a couple hundred dollars for after
that. And GitHub does that as well. If
they I think if they need to make a
documentation change, they'll they'll
pay you for it. So, it's not just like a
it doesn't feel like a cop out or
doesn't feel like as much of a cop out
to say, "Oh, oops, you caught us. Let's
just change the documentation instead of
fixing the bug." Like, okay, if it
actually is a if it actually is a
documentation bug, like whatever, but
yeah,
you still should get paid for for that.
Yeah. So, when choosing a a new program,
I assume you you take a look at the
documentation if it's if it's uh
extensive or not. What other things do
you pay attention to when when choosing
a new program to hack on?
Yeah, so this is kind of a an evolving
thing for me as I'm moving to full-time.
But, what I what I generally like to do
is when I'm sitting down to hack, if I
haven't already decided the night before
who I'm going to hack is I will look at
my my most recent uh invites. And so,
I'll get, you know, when you're active
on HackerOne, you'll get program invites
pretty frequently. And they're always
small programs, but I'll look at the
the ones I've gotten most recently and
I'll just go through those.
Spend about usually like an hour or so,
30 minutes to an hour, um just testing
it and seeing like, "Okay, is Do I think
that there's going to be bugs here?
Like, is this a complicated looking
permission structure? Are there lots of
IDs? Does this let people like self sign
up and then like add people to their to
their organization and or is it just
like a
is it just like an application where
people can apply for like a credit check
or apply for like a vehicle loan? It's
like, okay, maybe that's not going to be
as as
uh
as fruitful.
Um and so, after going through my new
like my my list of new programs and
saying, "Okay, these are the ones I'm
going to hack." Um after I've exhausted
all those, I'll go back to a
tried-and-true program that's generally
bigger that I have some uh experience on
and know kind of their their API. And
then, I'll sit there until either
I get like a live hacking event invite,
which, you know, moves all my focus to
the live hacking event target, or I get
like a new fresh invite that I that I
take a look at.
Yeah. And what do you look for after you
you look through the the bugs that we've
talked about today, which are
authorization bugs, maybe pebble
bypasses cuz on on your top program, I
see 168 reports.
So, I assume that's that's quite a lot a
lot more.
Yeah, so I
I also like to look for uh things that
are unique to that uh
application. So,
um
things like business logic errors. So,
maybe it's maybe it might not be
vulnerable to IDORs or privilege
escalations but it might have like a
like a feature that's really unique to
them and a really unique uh
I guess
a a attack surface. Like, maybe they
maybe it's an application that
really really cares about
um
PII. Like, they really really don't want
you to to know any users' names. And so,
if if that's if that's the case about
that application, I'll go and I'll look
through
the different endpoints and just see
where where can I get people's names? Is
there any way to use use this
application in a way that would leak
name information? Or maybe it's an
application where um
um
I'm having trouble thinking of like a
specific
scenario without giving something away.
Uh so, at the Capital One event
Capital One hacking event in in Miami,
the the application that I was hacking
on had a really unique attack surface
and things that they cared about, which
was I mean, I I can't talk about about
what it was, but it was a there was
something really unique about the target
that I was hacking on for that that
Miami event. And so, I just said,
"Okay." You know, IDORs, whatever.
Privilege escalations, whatever.
How can I accomplish this thing that
this particular application really
doesn't want me to do?" And that's just
where I spent spent all my time.
Um
Yeah.
Are these mostly
technical bugs cuz in in one of the
interviews, you said you cannot read
JavaScript. Uh so, do you look for for
bugs that let's say
business logic bugs that that usually
involve maybe changing the ID, changing
the parameters like like this, or are
you also looking for for these very
technical bugs?
Uh so, a lot My favorite bugs are the
non-technical ones. So, I can talk I can
talk about one uh without giving the the
target away, but I was hacking on this
on a store application.
And there was a
I wanted to find a way to get other
users' shipping addresses. And so, I was
like looking at the the invoices. I'm
like, "Okay, is there a way to like
there's a way to like buy things for
other people on this application?" And I
was like, "And have it shipped to them?"
But, the the address was obfuscated. And
so, I was like, "Oh, there's got to be a
way to there's got to be a way to uh
to get that, you know, to get some
that victim user's address by like
buying something for them." And so, so
what uh what me and my team did, I was
working with uh Space Raccoon at the
time
uh and Alex Chapman, I believe. Um
And what we did was we
decided, "Okay, this this user's going
to be our victim user. Here's their
address. We'll just like put in a search
filter on like Burp Suite."
And then, we went through every type of
functionality we could think of. Like,
"Okay, can we
can we buy something for this person as
like a gift and then cancel it? And
then, maybe the cancellation notice will
show like the shipping address?" And
eventually, we found a very obscure old
piece of functionality
which allowed
um
I I guess I can't can't go into too much
detail without giving the program away.
But, uh we found a very old piece of
functionality which
let you buy something for somebody in a
non-traditional way.
And then, the invoice when you did it
that way included the the victim's
shipping address. And so, this wasn't
using like aside from just doing like a
search filter on Burp like this wasn't
using like any any payloads. It wasn't
modifying any IDs. We were just using
the application with just a mouse and a
keyboard. And we eventually found a way
using some obscure old piece of
functionality that I didn't even know
existed at the time like until then to
get
pretty business-critical information and
or
business-critical information that the
uh the business really cared about
keeping users' home addresses, you know,
private. And so, using this
vulnerability, we were able to
effectively leak the home address of
every single user on the application.
Which was Yeah, they and they paid it
out as a critical.
Yeah, that's a cool approach to to just
focus on one particular
impact that you want to achieve a
leaking particular piece of information
and and focusing the the efforts for
some time and just doing this. I don't
think I've ever done this.
It sounds like
So, I call that treasure I call it
treasure hunting.
Yeah, I I call I call it treasure
hunting where it's like rather than
looking just all across for
vulnerabilities, you have like one piece
of treasure that you're looking for. And
you're just thinking, "Okay, how can I
achieve
X?" And you just go all in on finding X.
You might be ignoring like other
vulnerabilities, but if you if you've
identified that treasure that you want
and you know it's going to pay a pay a
critical, then yeah, you just go all in
on it and maybe spend a day or two. And
um there's
more than likely going to be going to be
a way to achieve it. Maybe it'll be like
a bit complicated and require some like
user interaction or maybe it will
require having slightly elevated
permissions, but there's there's going
to be a way to to find that treasure.
Yeah, and for sure you will you come up
with more ideas when you focus on one
goal rather than when you just hunt
normally and look for the functionality
and look for let's say more or less the
same ideas that you do in different
apps.
Uh but when you when you have just you
know I want to leak this I imagine you
do much more different things to to
achieve this and and that that's sounds
like a perfect way to
to find bugs that the others would would
miss.
Exactly. Exactly. And it's just so
rewarding, right? When you finally when
you finally find it. Like when I finally
leaked that address it was it was so
satisfying it was so satisfying
cuz just cuz the impact was so big, you
know, being able to get find out where
anybody lives that uses the application.
Oh, it was
it was so cool.
Yeah.
Uh one concept I want to talk about I
saw on your on your blog post and I
really really liked it is the concept of
embedded hackers and I'd like all
potential program managers or people
from platforms to to hear about this.
So, can you please talk about what you
meant in that blog post?
Yes, yeah, I'm I'm happy to. I'm happy
to. I'm happy to cuz this this had come
up just recently a situation where I
really wish this was the case. So,
there's there's times where you go
really really deep on an application.
Like I know that you are really familiar
with that application that you were
telling me about over over Twitter DMs
where you found your bug. And sometimes
the application has a lot of
functionality and it's really complex.
What's really really frustrating is
filing your report on something that you
know, like you know the application like
the back of your hand. You know how to
use it. The program really knows it and
so all you need to say is yeah, just
like make a user set them as this type
of user and then hit this endpoint. But
then you like triage comes in as because
the company program's paying for triage
and they don't know the application like
you do. They don't know the application
like the the program does. And so
they're going to say, okay, you say you
make this a user with this this level of
permissions. Can you tell me how to make
a user? Can you tell me how to
to create this document that you say you
need to be able to create to exploit the
vulnerability. Can you Can you tell me
how to create an organization? And it's
like you have to kind of give them a
primer on how to use the application to
even find your bug when you know, the
program knows, the only person who
doesn't know is the triager. And so what
I my concept of embedded hackers
is to let programs choose specific
hackers that they
like the reports, they trust them
to
and just have that those hackers reports
be you bypass the triage process because
you know, maybe
uh you know, maybe they know like this
particular program that I I've got 168
reports on. I just had to like put out a
response of to a triager to explain how
to use the app how to use the
application and how to sign in as a
specific type of user. And it was
frustrating cuz
like I know how to do it and the program
knows how to do it. And so if this
program can say, yes, Douglas Day or
Archangel has submitted 168 reports to
us. He knows how to use the application.
Just
make sure his report you
I'm not going to submit garbage. I'm not
going to submit reports that aren't
valid. I've submitted 168 reports
already. It's like
I my report should be able to go
directly to the program. And so this
benefits triage because they're not
having as much work to do and they can
focus on their their efforts on
programs that need the help. It benefits
me because I don't have to wait as long
and it benefits the program because if
I'm like submitting a critical
vulnerability that they really care
about then they can get it faster and
they can fix it faster. Like the last
thing I want is for like
uh a program like um
I I don't know. I think I think PayPal
uses uses HackerOne's triage but I you
know, the last thing I want is for
you know, PayPal to um
get like a critical or you know,
vulnerability reported on you know,
reported by a hacker who maybe is knows
PayPal very well and is very trusted.
But then you know, the the vulnerability
is
complicated or the the functionality is
complicated so that it takes longer for
them for the vulnerability to get to
PayPal because you know, triage is just
having to kind of understand
how this particular piece of
functionality works. So,
by
by having programs just opt in specific
hackers to bypass the triaging process,
I think it would make all all people
happy.
Yeah. Were you able to implement this as
elastic?
Uh
unofficially
um the HackerOne platform didn't have
anything native but when we saw like
reports come in from
hackers that we had
trusted like particularly like DC
um was one of our big our big hackers.
Um Dominic, he's based in
Ireland now, I think.
Um
but he whenever we saw see something
coming from him, we just grab it out of
the queue because you know, elastic is a
complicated piece of functionality or
complicated piece of technology. Um I
don't expect triagers to know how to use
elastic search.
Um and so if
but you know, DC Dominic knows how to
use elastic search. We know how to use
elastic search. And so he submitted
something to us. I didn't want there to
be a delay because a triager doesn't
know how to use elastic search.
Yeah. Yeah, I really like the concept
and I think
it's especially annoying with open
source targets which which I like to
hack on cuz then often I have to explain
to the triager how to even set up the
application.
And and once they get through this,
sometimes they will ask questions. Let's
say recently I submitted a report that
I was not sure what the company will say
about it cuz it was quite quite a
complex one.
So, I was like, I don't know if if you
want to triage this or not.
But the thing is the questions that
triager was asking me after they they
set up the application, the the
questions they were asking me about the
bug
were not the questions that that were
bothering me and I knew it will will be
important for the company whether this
bug is is valid or not in their
particular setup.
And
yeah, so I really like this concept. I
would love this this to be implemented.
And I also one one more thing is
when talking to a program, I feel like
we can very well communicate
through the source code on the on the
source open source application. When I
show to the program the the source code,
you know, here's the vulnerable piece of
code. Here is why this works.
They will understand it and and perhaps
they don't even have to
to reproduce the bug. Maybe for for the
sanity they they want to reproduce the
bug but they will see the source code
and they will know why the bug is there
and the triager usually you know, goes
pre pre needs to to actually verify this
which is just time consuming, you know.
I'm not saying anything back bad cuz I
know setting up the application is
really difficult sometimes but I just
think I shouldn't be the person that
helps the triager to to do this. Yeah.
Yeah, I agree.
So, I have to ask as as an open source
hacker, have you done like the ultimate
flex and written a like a PR fix to go
with your report?
Um no. No, I didn't I didn't do this.
I
I just I sometimes fantasize about about
doing that and how cool it would look to
be like, here's your bug. Also, here's
the fix.
So, I I did not submit the PR but once I
was submitting a zero day we were collab
collaborating I think with Nagli to
report a zero day across different
programs.
Um and in the report I would give the
monkey patch to to the
clients using the the target
application. So,
that was the the closest that I did but
never actually did did a fix. I would be
happy to
to suggest a fix if there was additional
incentive but just for
for the for the
for fun of it. No, I didn't
never did it.
Okay, I will be heading to to end our
conversation. So, did I understand
correctly today is 9th July 9th July and
you from the beginning of August you
will be a full-time bug bounty hunter.
Uh no, I'm a I'm a full-time bug bounty
hunter now as of
June
June 26th, I think. Oh, so it's already
been So, I've been been a full-time
full-time bug bounty hunter for a couple
weeks, yeah.
How is it going?
Uh yeah, I think it's going I think it's
going well. There are some challenges
and changes that I'm I'm getting used
to. Namely, it's very difficult to judge
my productivity um
based on like a dollar amount because I
could say like, yeah, I worked 8 hours
today and you know, maybe I got you
maybe I found three bugs but those bugs
might not get paid until next month. And
so do I to kind of
have metric excuse me, have metrics
around how
well I'm doing, do I
total the amount of bounties I'm getting
paid each week or do I total the number
of bugs that I'm getting finding each
week and reporting which may or may not
be paid. And so I can I can keep track
of, okay, I got paid, you know,
you know, $10,000 in bounties this week.
But those $10,000 might have been like
from bugs that I reported like
the a month ago. And so I don't it's
really difficult to keep track of, okay,
how how productive am I being? How do I
need to change? What do I need to to
adjust to to make sure that I'm like
meeting my meeting my bounty quotas. And
that's kind of been a a very interesting
very interesting change is yeah, just
keeping track of of how I'm doing
money-wise. So, that's kind of the the
biggest challenge uh
that and
as I kind of delve more into consulting
having appropriate bound boundaries with
and expectations with with customers I'm
I'm doing consulting and pen testing
with um and you know, not
necessarily responding to like emails in
the middle of the night um even though
they're from somebody who's expecting a
uh pen test report soon. So, yeah,
that's kind of the
a couple of challenges, but obviously
the the benefits outweigh the
the the negatives.
Yeah. Yeah, I can't wait to to interview
again in a year or two and and see what
things from the
life of a full-time bug bounty hunter
surprise you the most, what was exactly
as you expected and
what change did you actually develop the
automation? I think it would be really
really fun to to see what changed after
after going full-time.
Yeah, that'll be fun. Like July of next
year, see how I'm doing. Maybe I'll be
maybe I'll be back in a job or maybe
I'll have
started my own company. I don't know.
We'll see.
Uh
but yeah, it's kind of a
I'm taking a risk, but I mean the best
things in life require risk. So,
uh we'll see how it goes.
Yeah, and people if if we don't if we
don't publish it 2025 by let's say by
the end of July, you can ping us on on
Twitter too.
So, that we we record this this
interview. For now, Douglas, thank you
so much for the interview. I wish you
all the best in your full-time bug
bounty hunter journey. Thanks, Greg.
Yeah, this has been a real treat.
Pleasure talking with you as always and
uh good luck to your team in the World
Cup and we'll uh we'll see you in the
finals. Yeah, see you see you in the
finals.
Bye.
If you've learned something during this
episode, just go and test it on a real
website because I know for a fact that
it works. But if you can't do it right
now, I recommend you to listen to this
episode with David Schütz. For now,
thank you for listening and goodbye.